# **ERSAKANTI BELVA**

# Software Engineer

Surabaya, Indonesia | Phone: (+62) 821-4605-5951 | email: <a href="mailto:ersakantibelva@gmail.com">ersakantibelva@gmail.com</a> LinkedIn: <a href="mailto:Ersakanti Belva">Ersakanti Belva</a> | Github: <a href="mailto:Ersakanti Belva">Ersakanti Belva</a>

# **Summary**

A female developer with an engineering degree who is passionate and interested in software development and an IT enthusiast. I joined Hacktiv8 Bootcamp as a student of Full-Stack JavaScript to enrich my technical or soft skills, such as JavaScript as the main programming language, developing servers using ExpressJs, and developing client-side websites using front-end frameworks (ReactJs, VueJs). Moreover, I learned to work under pressure individually and as part of a team while I was a head of a department in a previous organization. I also learned to have high dedication, responsibility towards my work, and eagerness to learn new things. I hope to further develop my experience by working as a software engineer in the future.

#### **Education**

Sept 2022 - Jan 2023 Remote

# **Certificate Transcript**

**Full-Stack JavaScript Student** 

Hacktiv8 Indonesia

- Learned programming and software development fundamentals.
- Developed websites through projects assignments both server-side and client-side.

Award: Teacher's Awards Final Grade: 96.8%

Aug 2022 - Sept 2022 Remote

#### Certificate

Mar 2022 – Sept 2022 Remote

**Certificate Completion** 

#### **React Js Web Frontend Student**

Sanbercode

- Learned developing client-side website using React Js
- Developed website using authentication and deployment with Netlify

#### **Data Analyst Track Participant**

Generasi GIGIH 2.0 by GoTo

- Learned about Data Ecosystem, Data Analytic, Statistics, Data Processing using SQL, Python Programming (Numpy and Pandas), and Data Visualization with Google Data Studio.
- Developed soft skills such as Adaptability, Time Management, Constructive Feedback, Critical Thinking, Life Path, Problem Solving, etc.
- Worked on a Capstone Project that collaborates with stakeholder and is fully engaged as a part of the engineering team.

Jul 2018 – August 2022 Surabaya, Indonesia

## **Undergraduate, Engineering Physics**

Sepuluh Nopember Institute of Technology

- Relevant Coursework: Computer Programming
- **GPA**: 3.63/4.00
- **Final Project**: Type-2 Fuzzy Logic System Model Design for Determination of M-Learning Usage Behavior Based On The Self-Efficacy and Facilitating Conditions Room Lighting Facility (Score: A)

#### **Experience**

May 2022 – August 2022 Remote

#### **Data Analyst Intern**

PT Gizi Sehat Indonesia (Dietela.id)

- Successfully analyzed over 400 Dietela's clients and created the dashboard to get an overview of client demographics and personas using Google Data Studio and Python with Pandas
- Accomplished to use Natural Language Processing (NLP) to process the data with text type using Sastrawi library

Nov 2020 – Dec 2021 Surabaya, Indonesia

## **Head of Communication and Information Department**

Himpunan Mahasiswa Teknik Fisika, ITS

- Responsible for conceptualizing 5 departmental work programs that run for 10 months.
- Succeeded in creating a social media content scheduling management system for Instagram and LINE Official Accounts.
- Rewarded as one of the Best Departments in HMTF ITS 2020/2021

Feb 2021 – Jan 2022 Surabaya, Indonesia

#### **Staff of Brand and Information Management**

AIESEC in Surabaya

- Produced branding content of AIESEC in Surabaya on Instagram and LinkedIn.
- Awarded the title of Member of The Month in February and March for the Staff category.
- Succeeded in drafting more than 20 contents in a month.
- Enabled to get a 25% increase in followers for 5 months.

#### **Technical Skills**

**Programming Language** 

Javascript, Python

Front End

ReactJs, React Native, VueJs, Pinia, HTML, CSS, TailwindCSS, Bootstrap, Expo, Redux, Redux-Thunk, jQuery, EJS, Axios, Ajax

Back End Node.js, Express, REST API, JSON Web Tokens (JWT), Redis, GraphQL,

Apollo, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, Unit Testing (Jest and

Supertest), Microservices

Others Github, Gitlab, Firebase, AWS EC2, Docker, Railway, Heroku, Supabase,

Socket.io, MATLAB, Microsoft Office, Google Data Studio, Google

Colaboratory, Google Suites, BigQuery, IBM SPSS

# **Projects**

Linguagram

Dec 2022

Chat-based web application that connects users who want to learn languages together. This app was developed by the final-project

team in Hacktiv8.

Tech Stack: ReactJs, Redux, TailwindCSS, ExpressJs, Socket.io,

PostgreSQL

This Is August - E Commerce

Clone App (ReactJs)
Dec 2022

E-commerce cloned app with two client-side website: admin dashboard and main website. Built with Reactjs as main frontend

library.

Tech Stack: ReactJs, Redux, React Router DOM, TailwindCSS,

ExpressJs, PostgreSQL

This is August - Mobile App

(React Native)

Dec 2022

The mobile app for cloning e-commerce. Built with microservice

architecture.

Tech Stack: React Native, Redux, ExpressJs, Apollo (GraphQl),

PostgreSQL, MongoDb, Redis, Docker, AWS

**HackFit - Social Media App** 

Nov 2022

A fitness social media website where user can upload their current fitness activity to other users. Users can create a post and like the other posts. There is also leveling feature for each user. The more

difficult the activity, user can get more score.

Tech Stack: VueJs, Pinia, Express, Multer, Nodemailer,

PostgreSQL, Sequelize

**HacktivMart - ECommerce App** 

Oct 2022

E-commerce app, focusing on groceries products. Use basic CRUD with authentication and authorization based on the type of

user.

Tech Stack: Express, EJS, Sequelize